A big welcome to ALL the fans
watching out there around the globe!
We are so excited to be presenting  the
2023 Crunchyroll Anime Awards tonight!
For the first time ever, we are  bringing
you the Anime Awards from Japan!
We're here at the Grand
Prince Hotel  Shin Takanawa,
where we've achieved something unprecedented.
Tonight we've gathered some of  the
biggest names in anime in one room!
The world has changed so much
over the last few years,
so now more than ever,
it's vitally important  that
the creators and artists
who dream up so many of our favorite anime
understand the influence  they
have on the fans around the world,
and how much they've done
to brighten people's lives!
Like so many of you,  anime is
an important part of my life,
and being a big fan myself,
I'm honored to be a part
of this thriving community.
The people presenting the awards tonight
are stars from all over the world
all over the world and all  walks
of life - from athletes to actors,
mega-influencers to major directors
to comedians and content creators -
everyone here tonight considers themselves
huge anime fans and are ready to celebrate!
This year creators have reached  new
levels of their incredible talent -
so let me tell you -
determining the recipients  of
each award was no easy feat!
No, it really wasn't.
What's wonderful is that passionate anime fans
from  all over the world voted for their favorites!
18 MILLION votes were cast overall
and determined the Grand Winners.
Indeed.
Ok, so let's get to the reason
we're all here tonight –
celebrating the anime  that
has inspired, thrilled,
entertained and completely
wowed us this year.
Let's kick off this big night with someone
who has always supported  the anime
industry and the art of storytelling.
Yes.
No one knows how important it
is  to change hearts and minds
through the power of
creativity and technology
more than the Chairman, President and CEO
of  Sony Group Corporation – Kenichiro Yoshida!
Good evening, everyone.  I'm Kenichiro
Yoshida, CEO of Sony Group.
Welcome to the 2023 Crunchyroll Anime Awards!
This year marks the 7th year of this award
that honors the achievements of anime works
and creators through voting of anime fans.
Many of the stories  and
characters that evoke empathy,
including more than  50
TV and theatrical titles
by over 30 studios selected for these awards,
were born here in Japan.
We are thrilled and honored to be able to
host  a global celebration of anime here in Japan,
with our creators, our fans who are
joining through Crunchyroll's livestream,
and our partners  who are
here with us tonight.
Anime has become an entertainment
with a global cultural force.
Currently, nearly 300 million
fans  around the world
are enjoying anime on streaming services.
This is nearly double  to
what it was 2 years ago,
and the anime fan communities
are growing at this very moment.
At Crunchyroll,
we are also contributing to spreading  the
Kando (emotions) of anime to the world,
together with our partners.
Entertainment has the
power  to connect people.
And we feel that there is  social
significance in expanding Kando.
But this is not possible without
the passionate people behind anime.
I would like to express my sincere respect
for the creative community who lead us to
the world of dreams that exceed our imagination
and give us the pleasure
of experiencing them.
And lastly, this award is only
possible because of the fans
who have voted in over
200 countries and regions.
We would like to thank each and everyone
of you for your whole-hearted support.
Your energy is our driving force,
to expand the Kando of anime.
I feel extremely grateful to be able to
share the magnificence of
anime with everyone tonight.
Thank you very much, please enjoy the show.
Thank you, Yoshida-san!  Such
inspiring words for tonight!
Okay! Fasten your seatbelts -
it's time for our first award!
He's an entertainer, an entrepreneur
–  and when it comes to anime,
there's no way around it -  if
you've watched his YouTube channel,
you already know he's definitely a superfan!
Here to present the award  for
“Best Original Anime…”
Please welcome, the one and only ROLAND!
Hello to everyone in Japan.
And those of you watching worldwide,
nice to meet you, I'm ROLAND.
I know some of you may be thinking,
"What is ROLAND doing here?"
But I am actually a huge fan of
anime. On my YouTube channel,
there was an episode where I'd wear
disguise to walk around in Akihabara.
That's how much I love anime.
I also love original anime as well,
so I'm very happy to be the
presenter of this category.
Now, let us take a look at all
the nominees for this category.
I'll announce the grand winner.
I have the result in my hand.
I'm going to savor this moment
as I slowly open this envelope.
And the Anime Award goes to...
Lycoris Recoil.
- Congratulations. - Thank you very much.
I didn't think I'd be the first
one to make a speech up here.
I'm not fully prepared mentally.
But I'm happy that
among such fine works we just saw,
my work was chosen.
I'm grateful to all the fans and
the Crunchyroll Anime Awards.
Thank you so much.
With original anime, we have to start
from when there is zero audience for it.
So it is not an easy battle.
But no matter what genre, what
title, having the opportunity to
create multiple episodes of
original anime from scratch,
we, the anime creators, appreciate
that type of experience.
And so,
please give us more chance to
create even more original anime.
That will help us anime creators grow.
I hope that it becomes a movement.
Thank you very much.
To present the award for
“Best Character Design”
is a very talented actress and member
of the pop idol group Nogizaka46.
She is also known as a huge anime fan.
Please welcome Haruka Kaki!
When it comes to anime, the
most inspiring characters
are the ones that are SO unique
you can recognize them immediately
just from a small detail.
Maybe it’s their posture, their smirk,
an iconic hairstyle or the unmistakable
way they wield their weapon.
Just one look at how they’re drawn- and
you immediately understand their full story.
That’s the gift of great artistry.
Here are the nominees for
Best Character Design.
I'm honored to announce the grand winner.
And the Anime Award goes to...
Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba
Entertainment District Arc.
Congratulations!
I'm a little bit nervous because
I'm not used to doing this.
I'm Katsuyuki Konishi,
and I am the voice actor
for the role of Uzui Tengen in Demon Slayer.
The characters in Demon Slayer are
truly beautiful, if I may say so.
They are absolutely gorgeous,
and their facial expressions,
accessories they wear,
everything is so detailed.
And they're not just beautiful.
Each is imbued with so much,
like the character's soul.
And I believe that resonated
with the fans worldwide.
Let that be my speech for
accepting this award.
Since I'm a voice actor, I'm not
involved in the making of animation,
but I will make sure to
deliver this to the creators.
Thank you very much!
To present the award for “Best
Animation” is a comic actor
who has played so many of our
favorite anime characters
that when we hear his voice
we don’t know if we should laugh
or fight him in an epic battle!
Please welcome Kendo Kobayashi.
Hello, I'm Kendo Kobayashi.
Animation is more than drawing or painting,
it’s a visual feast for the eyes-
the rules of the real world can be
broken in a way we didn't even imagine,
or, we have a slice-of-life,
relax-and-chill genre of anime.
All the great creators in this room know
that great leaps forward in innovation
and visually stunning artistry only
happen when someone takes a big risk.
And tonight proves that taking
big risks earns big rewards
not only do they gain a passionate
fan following worldwide,
but also the respect of everyone
in the anime community.
Here are the nominees for Best Animation.
Okay.
And the Anime Award goes to...
Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba
Entertainment District Arc.
- Congratulations. - Thank you very much.
Thank you for this wonderful award.
I'm Yuma Takahashi, the producer
of Demon Slayer at Aniplex.
Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba
-Entertainment District Arc and To the Swordsmith Village
is currently touring worldwide,
delivering it to Japanese
fans and global fans.
And we've been blessed with the
chance to see fans face-to-face.
Just the other day, Mr. Konishi
and I visited Germany and France.
We had the opportunity to
interact with local fans.
And every single fan's support
has led to this award.
I'd like to thank fans in
Japan and all over the world.
And more importantly, we
have fans' support thanks to
voice actors like Mr. Konishi,
as well as everyone at ufotable
who made this anime possible.
So I will deliver this trophy to ufotable.
Thank you very much.
Now, here to present the award
for “Best Continuing Series,”
please welcome two titans
of American Football
professional athletes Aiden Hutchinson
and Juju Smith-Schuster!
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
One Piece usually gets nominated to these
things but never receives anything.
All the staff work very hard
to turn this wonderful title
into an anime to deliver to our fans.
But quite often, it's difficult to
visualize and recognize that effort.
So being acknowledged publicly
like this truly motivates us.
The series is going to get even
more exciting from here on,
and this will really encourage the staff.
We want to tell the world what
an amazing story One Piece is.
And all the staff, voice
actors, producers and others,
will do our best to make it happen!
Please cheer for us! Thank you!
Valentine’s Day was just a few weeks ago
but every day is Valentine’s Day
when you have love in your heart!
So let’s keep the spirit
of the holiday all year long
by announcing the nominees for Best Romance.
Here to do that – she’s
a WWE Superstar…
and he’s one of the stars of Cobra Kai
please welcome Zelina
Vega and Jacob Bertrand!
I'm Aoi Koga, and I'm the voice
actor for Kaguya Shinomiya
in Kaguya-sama: Love is War.
I'm so honored to receive
such a wonderful award
at a ceremony like this.
Thank you very much.
This anime series, Kaguya-sama:
Love is War, is
seen worldwide, showcasing romance in Japan
and how Japanese boys and girls
go through love games
in a comedic way.
It can make you cry, it can make you laugh.
It's packed with lots of drama.
The original manga is also wonderful.
Aka Akasaka-sensei gave
us fantastic characters,
and we were blessed with incredible
staff, and I'm extremely thankful.
As creators, we worked very hard together
with passion and love for the series.
I'm so grateful to everyone on the team.
Also!
A heart-felt thank you to all the fans in
the world who love and support this series.
Thank you so much.
Coming up – Kohta Yamamoto
performs “Ashes on the Fire”
from Attack on Titan:
the Final Season Part 1!
And Finn and Nick Wolfhard present
the award for Best Fantasy.
Plus, Kendo Kobayashi,
Zelina Vega, Sawa Suzuki,
Robert Rodriguez, Justin Lin and more.
When the 2023 Crunchyroll
Anime Awards returns!
Welcome back.
Now, put your hands together for
a special musical performance –
here to commemorate the dark fantasy
“Attack on Titan Final Season Part 1”
and its achievement of "Anime of the
Year" at Crunchyroll Anime Awards 2022…
This is Kohta Yamamoto performing the score
that he composed, "Ashes On The Fire."
Are you all having a good time?
As you have seen, tonight is not just a
celebration of all the incredible creators of anime,
but also the army of fervent
fans across the world…
fans who live, breathe and dream anime…
fans who energize this world with
their loyalty and love of the artform.
Throughout the night, we’ll visit a few
anime fans and hear their story first-hand.
Take a look!
Here to present  the award
for “Best Fantasy” -
from the new anime film  Goodbye
Don Glees – Nick Wolfhard…
and from the worldwide juggernaut
Stranger Things… Finn Wolfhard!
It's my second time up here, so I'm
trying to come up with what to say.
But first and foremost,
to the fans worldwide,
thank you for your votes.
We're lucky to be nominated
in multiple categories,
and it proves that the
worldview and the message
of Demon Slayer spoke to people all over the world.
It is a story about bonds, between
Tanjiro and Nezuko, or amongst friends.
And Tanjiro is truly strong, he's
tenacious and he perseveres.
I really hope that witnessing his
strength helps anime fans everywhere
with something with their
lives. Thank you very much.
To present the award for Best Comedy,
please welcome back Kendo Kobayashi.
Thank you for having me again.
Great anime humor affects us.
Regardless of who you are, where you
live  or what language you speak,
it can makes us laugh.
We're always waiting for
great humor like that.
These outstanding anime
series  we celebrate tonight
will do just that, it's funny
for anyone in the world.
Here are the nominees for Best Comedy.
And the Anime Award goes to...
SPY x FAMILY!
Even if you live in Tokyo, you
don't see celebrities up close
like this too often, so
I'm so honored and happy.
Allow me to say a little
bit about the series.
So we won the best comedy.
Uniting the world through
laughter and comedy...
I haven't worked with too many
comedies in my career, but
thanks to the amazing original manga, the series
turned out fun, not to mention the creative process.
The process as stress-free, and I
enjoyed working on it every day.
And to be awarded like this... I sit at my
desk and work all day, so this is nerve-wracking.
This must be the peak of my life.
Considering my age, it's safe
to say that this is my peak.
So thank you for the wonderful memory.
Straight ahead – Yuki Kajiura
performs a hit song from Demon Slayer!
And who will take home  the
Anime Award for Best Score?
Plus, Hunter Schafer, Robert Rodriguez,
Justin Lin, Valkyrae and Sykkuno and more!
This is the 2023 Crunchyroll Anime Awards!
Welcome back!
Now, from one of the most popular manga  of
all time to a juggernaut anime series, film,
and fan favorite, Demon Slayer
has taken the world by storm.
Here to perform the “Homura,” the hit
theme  song to Demon Slayer the Movie: Mugen Train,
please welcome famed composer
and music artist, Yuki Kajiura!
Congratulations on  the
Crunchyroll Anime Awards.
I'm honored for the invitation.
As LiSA could not perform today,
we performed on her behalf,
I hope you enjoyed our performance.
Now – our next presenter
is such a huge fan of anime,
she inspired the producers
to make her character in  the hit
show Euphoria a big anime fan too!
Listen to these other accomplishments:
she's the voice of Ruka in the English
version of the anime film Belle.
And she can next be seen  starring
in the highly anticipated film,
The Hunger Games:  The Ballad
of Songbirds and Snakes.
Joining us remotely to announce
the award for Best Score,
here is actress and artist Hunter Schafer!
Congratulations!
Thank you for the introduction.
I'm KOHTA YAMAMOTO, the composer for
Attack on Titan: the Final Season Part 2.
And this is Hiroyuki Sawano, who's been
composing for the series since Season 1.
I'd like to speak on behalf of both of us.
I never expected that we would be receiving
such a wonderful award today,
so we're both quite surprised.
It's hard to believe that
it's happening for real.
The Final Chapters Special
1 just aired last night.
We're approaching the climax of the story.
Seeing the broadcast last
night, I could tell that
the creators poured everything they
had on it, and it was magnificent.
And I'm truly honored that
I get to be a part of it.
I'd like to thank everyone who
made this series possible.
Thank you very much.
I'm honored to be standing in to
receive this. Congratulations!
So if I may read this message
on behalf of the winner...
Confirming that I am reading it.
My heart is racing.
Thank you, Crunchyroll! Thank you,
SiM's fans all over the world!
I regret that we can't attend
the ceremony in person,
but I'm honored that we received this award.
Numbers of amazing anime
songs were released in 2022.
"The Rumbling" was released early
in the year, on January 10th.
And the fact that it never lost
its impact throughout the year
brings me an incomparable joy as a composer.
But it was thanks to the epic story of
Attack on Titan that gave birth to this song
not to mention characters' words, facial
expressions, every little details.
So first and foremost, we'd like to
send the biggest respect and gratitude
to Hajime Isayama-sensei, the
creator of this great series.
We're also grateful for MAPPA, who chose
SiM to accompany the incredible animation.
Lastly, there is one thing I must say.
SiM is a rock band.
So we want you to come to our concert
and listen to "The Rumbling" live!
We've booked tours all around the world.
Come to our live concert!
That's all! MAH!
Now I'm back to being the host.
Now, here to present  the
award for Best Film is
an acclaimed actor of so many  of
our favorite movies and shows –
Sawa Suzuki.
Congratulations on the 2023
Crunchyroll Anime Awards in Japan.
Hello everyone, I'm Sawa Suzuki.
Whether you're in a dark movie theater or
snuggled down in the comfort of your couch,
a truly masterful film will
sweep you away to another world.
These are this year's nominees for Best Film.
And the Anime Award goes to...
JUJUTSU KAISEN 0!
President Otsuka was supposed to
come up here with me... Anyhow!
First of all, what an honor
to receive such an award!
I'm truly happy, thank you very much!
Pardon my late introduction, my
name is Matsutani, from Toho.
I am one of the producers of the film.
Receiving support from the
fans worldwide like this,
for them to enjoy and love this film so much,
I'm glad to see it visualized
in the form of this award.
This film is based on the incredible
original work by Gege Akutami-sensei.
And MAPPA turned it into anime with
unparalleled focus and passion.
With the help of the director,
creators, other staff members,
the cast, and music artists for theme songs,
everyone helped to make this film amazing.
We also had support from
Shueisha, the publisher,
as well as the production committee.
Everyone involved was highly
motivated and engaged.
We were blessed to have all
of that to create this film.
In July, Season 2 will begin.
We will work hard with everyone
involved to create another hit
to make fans all over the world happy
so that they will support us in return.
Please continue to watch
Jujutsu Kaisen. Thank you.
Coming up – ALI is here
with special guest Aklo
to perform their single  “Lost in
Paradise”  from Jujutsu Kaisen.
Plus, the awards for Best
Director  and Anime of the Year!
Here, on the 2023 Crunchyroll Anime Awards!!
Now it's time to throw  things
back a little - but don't worry -
it's not TOO far back -
just a couple of years…
Next up is a special performance
commemorating Jujutsu Kaisen Season
1,  Cour one's achievement of
"Anime of the Year"  and
"Best Ending Sequence" from
the Crunchyroll Anime Awards back in 2021!
This is definitely getting us excited about
Jujutsu Kaisen Season 2 airing in July!
Performing the ending song  “Lost in
Paradise” featuring Aklo, here's Ali.
Take it away!
Thank you for this opportunity!
Hi.
Thanks to Crunchyroll and
others, we were able to
deliver our music to people
all over the world.
Along with Jujutsu Kaisen, we had
the honor of leaving our name
in history for years to come as we gave
birth to a song and received an award like this,
and have worked together with
you, I'm honored as a Japanese.
And my idol, Director
Robert Rodriguez is here.
I'm so happy I could give
up my fee for this gig.
Thank you again for this opportunity.
And I hope that music, anime, and films will
continue to be there for
you when you need them
as we create a peaceful world.
ALI, let's begin!
I am truly honored to
welcome  our next presenter.
He's the acclaimed director of huge movies
like Machete, From Dusk
Til Dawn,  and Spy Kids,
Oh boy, my left contact lens just fell off!
Therefore, I can hardly read what
I'm supposed to be saying right now.
But as you may know, a
strongest anime character
can enhance their power
by using only one eye.
Likewise, I'm going to close
one eye to read, if I may.
Excuse me.
Watching anime is going to help
me get out of this trouble.
But what energizes passionate
anime fans everywhere
isn't just the works I mentioned,
but it is Alita: Battle Angel.
To present the award for Best Director,
please welcome Robert Rodriguez!
Thank you for this wonderful award.
I wish Director Sotozaki and
the creators from ufotable
could come here and receive this award,
but currently, they are working hard on
the new season, To the Swordsmith Village,
as we speak.
So I am standing here on their behalf.
To have a director receive an award like this
is such a wonderful thing.
Starting with the director,
every single creator involved in the show
from character designers to
animators who draw background,
is necessary to complete the whole series.
And I'm glad that it is
being acknowledged globally.
And this series is made
available to the world
thanks to the work of Chrunchyroll.
I'm grateful for this platform
which makes it possible for global fans
to appreciate the works of
the director and other creators.
I will deliver this trophy to the director
and other creators at the studio.
Thank you very much!
Please allow me to take time to say this.
Didn't Sally handle the situation
with such wit and grace earlier?
I was thoroughly impressed.
Sally, thank you! She's in
the backstage right now.
Thank you.
Before we present the last award of the
evening, it’s our pleasure to welcome someone
someone who is no stranger to
Japan and draws much
of his inspiration from the world of
anime in his own creative life.
Please welcome to the stage, the
celebrated director of massive films
such as Star Trek Beyond as well as many
of the Fast and Furious movies,
including The Fast and the Furious: Tokyo
Drift - writer, producer and director,
Justin Lin.
Thank you, Justin.
Yes, we’ve climbed to the
top of the mountain and
come to the final award of the
night – Anime Of The Year!
Please welcome – two
wildly popular YouTubers,
Valkyrae and Sykkuno!
I'm Otsuka, the president of Studio Trigger.
Director Imaishi and other creators
were not able to attend today,
so I will receive this award on their behalf.
I'm quite shocked right now.
This series...
It is based on a video
game, "Cyberpunk 2077,"
and was created in collaboration
with CD Projekt Red.
An anime studio and a game developer,
between Japan and Poland,
so the collaboration was
beyond genres, beyond countries.
We have many heated conversations,
but neither of us backed down
and worked hard with passion.
I'm glad that it led to this award.
I'd like to say thank you
to every single person
who was involved in making
this series possible.
And to the fans who watched
and supported this series,
thank you so much from
the bottom of my heart.
Thank you for making our first Anime Awards in Tokyo
such a memorable night!
Did it become the night to be remembered
in the history of anime?
Thank you everyone here tonight in this room,
the creators, artists, producers,
musicians, the studios,
all of you for putting your heart
and soul into your work,
and everything you’ve done for Anime.
We look forward to everything you’ll
be creating this year and in the future!
And to our presenters and all the anime
fans around the world watching this,
thank you for joining us tonight!
We hope to see you again in 2024! Goodbye!